A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Linda Fingerson FA1201
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Linda Fingerson
1996-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Fingerson, Linda
Ford Foundation
FA1201
.76 Cubic Feet About 2 LTR size Hollinger boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Collection consists of one series.
Original order was maintained during processing.
The collection arrangement is as follows:
Series 1. Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) program administration files, 1996-1998
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necesary.
This material was transferred to the RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2018:065.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Other Finding Aids
Finding aids for collections related to Linda Fingerson's program administration work include:
FA1447 Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Jon Funabiki
FA540 Ford Foundation records, Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC), Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC), Office Files of John P. Santos
Biographical / Historical
Linda Fingerson supported the Ford Foundation's grant administration activities for nearly twenty years. Her Ford career began in 1990 when she worked as an Administrative Assistant in the Program Division. She was promoted to a Senior Administrative Assistant in 2000 and then promoted again in 2003 to become a Grants Administrator. She stayed in that position for six years until she departed the foundation in 2009.
Scope and Contents
Collections holds the subject files of Ford Foundation staff member Linda Fingerson. The records were created during Fingerson's time as an Administrative Assistant in the Program Division.
The collection consists of only one series. This series contains a group of subject files that Fingerson created to document her work supporting the administration of the Ford Foundation's Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) and its Media, Arts, and Culture Unit (MAC) between 1996 and 1998.
Ford Foundation; Program budgeting
- Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) program administration files, 1996-1998; 1; .76 Cubic Feet About 2 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series contains the files Linda Fingerson created to document her work supporting the administration of the Ford Foundation's Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) and its Media, Arts, and Culture Unit (MAC) between 1996 and 1998. Records generally regard EMAC meetings as well as different program and budget review activities conducted by the program's staff. The series also contains several office calendars of MAC Deputy Director Jon Funabiki and MAC Program Officer John Phillip Santos.
  Series chiefly consists of correspondence, notes, press clippings, and meeting briefing books.
  - Handouts - Non-grant related, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Transcription services, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Media, Arts, and Culture (MAC) Staff Meetings - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Melissa Carroll memo - Disbursements Procedures, 1997 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Project Information Management (PIM) info-net, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Art for 1997 biennial meeting, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) Staff Meeting, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - David Kearns luncheon - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    According to original folder, luncheon took place on November 3.
  - Anna Deavere Smith flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anna Deavere Smith flyers - Original, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Days, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture Program (EMAC) Program Budget Review briefing book, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) Annual Program Review Retreat, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - John Phillip Santos and Jon Funabiki office calendars, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
    Order of calendars in file:
    1. 1996-1997 (most likely Funabiki because Santos did not join the Ford Foundation until 1997) 2. 1996-1997 - Jon Funabiki 3. 1997-1998 - John Phillip Santos secretary calendar 4. 1997-1998 - Jon Funabiki 5. 1997-1998 - John Phillip Santos 6. 1998-1999 (mostly blank)